A Guide to the Paul Ehrlich and Martha Marquardt papers (Wellcome collection) FA136
Rockefeller Archive Center
- Paul Ehrlich Material, 1
  - Paul Ehrlich letters and blocks (Box 3, Folder 11)
    - Matters relating to 606
      - 1 sheet entitled "Salvarsan Präparate", not in Paul Ehrlich's handwriting (Box 3, Folder 11)
      - 6 typescript copies of letters by Ehrlich (Box 3, Folder 11)
        To: Althoff, 1901, 1906, 3x; Caro; Salomonsen, 1899; Unidentified.
  - Paul Ehrlich Reprints, 3 items (Box 3, Folder 12)
    "Die Werthbemessung des Diphtherie-Heilserums", Gustav Fischer, Jena, 1897, has C. H. B. initials on cover. "Toxin und Antitoxin", J. F. Lehmann, Munich, 1903, with dedication to Hedwig Ehrlich. "Chemotherapie von Infectionskrankheiten", Gustav Fischer, Jena, 1909.
  - Special Prints (Box 3, Folder 13)
    Booklet from the Accademia dei Lincei, 1908, referring to Paul Ehrlich. "Ehrlich-Kommers", Frankfurt, 1909. Program of celebration in honor of Ehrlich's Nobel Prize.
  - Paper clippings, 1910 1911 (Box 3, Folder 14)
    1910, 1911, regarding 606, including a copy of "Erenne Deine Krankheit", monthly journal for "sick and healthy people", 1910.
  - 60th Birthday articles, 11 items (Box 3, Folder 15)
    including a copy of each of the Berliner and Münchner Medicinische Wochenschrift. 1 page of the Berliner Illustrierte Zeitung: Was verdanken wir unseren Chemiken, which includes Paul Ehrlich.
  - Obituary notices (Box 3, Folder 16)
    Paper clippings and special issues of scientific journals with necrologies by: Bechthold, Berliner, Blaschko, Dreyfus, Friedlander, Hoffmann, Kirchner, Laquer, Leschke, A. Neisser, Pinkus, Posner, H. Sachs, C. Schleich, Thomsen, Wassermann.
  - Material regarding Paul Ehrlich's grave, 1947 (Box 3, Folder 17)
    1 photograph of Paul Ehrlich's grave covered with wreaths. 1 envelope containing a dried piece of heather labeled in Hedwig Ehrlich's hand, "von Paul Ehrlich's Grabe". Architectural drawing of Paul Ehrlich's gravesite dated 1947.
  - Material dealing with Salvarsan (Box 4, Folder 1)
    - 2 form letters regarding Salvarsan (one Sept. 1910) Form letter by Ehrlich dated Oct. 25, 1910, dealing with the application of Salvarsan
    - Lists of doctors who received 606
      - 2 lists with no date (printed), 1910 October-November (Box 4, Folder 1)
      - 1912 March, 2 items, (typed) (Box 4, Folder 1)
      - 1912 March-April, (typed) (Box 4, Folder 1)
      - 1913 February, (typed) (Box 4, Folder 1)
      - 2 lists not dated (typed), (one 32 pages, the other 4 pages) (Box 4, Folder 1)
      - French article about Salvarsan (Box 4, Folder 1)
      - Booklet called "Zusammenstellung von ärztlichen Presse-Äusserungen über Salvarsan", 1914 May (Box 4, Folder 1)
      - Reprint of article by W. Struve, member of parliament: "Die Salvarsan Frage", 1914 March 14 (Box 4, Folder 1)
      - Photocopy of the patent for derivatives of phenylarsenoxyds and arsenobenzols, 1907 April 9 (Box 4, Folder 1)
      - 2 photocopies of advertisements for Salvarsan (Box 4, Folder 1)
      - 2 photocopies of schematic drawing of organic arsenic compounds (Box 4, Folder 1)
      - 1 of trypan red (Box 4, Folder 1)
      - 1 photocopy of "therapeutic notices" about Salvarsan (Box 4, Folder 1)
      - 2 photocopies of cartoons about 606 (Box 4, Folder 1)
      - 6 postcards of 606 cartoons (Box 4, Folder 1)
      - Pages entitled "Syphilis und Salvarsan", 21 items typescript pages (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - Articles about Paul Ehrlich, 1916-1952; 21 items (Box 4, Folder 2)
    In papers or scientific journals covering the period.
  - Reprints of articles about Paul Ehrlich (Box 4, Folder 3)
    - Ascoli, Alberto, 1925
    - Bethe, Albrecht, 1947
    - Sachs, Hans, no date (reprint from "Schlesier des 18. and 19. Jahrhunderts"). Dem Andenken Paul Ehrlich's, 1917
    - Santinia, Francisco, 2 reports on 606, 1911 1912
    - Wassermann, 1909 August
    - Special issue of the Deutsche Medicinische Wochenschrift, article by Roux and Metchnikoff, honoring Behring at his 60th birthday
  - Photocopies of copy book indices (Box 4, Folder 4)
    Notes on copy books: Notes about transcripts of copy books, some handwritten transcripts done by Felix Pinkus before Martha Marquardt transcribed the copy books.
  - Paul Ehrlich desk Memorabilia (Box 5, Folder 5)
    - 1 inkblotter
    - untitled
      1 container with sponge.
    - 1 wooden inkstand with 2 glass ink wells
    - 1 long pen holder
    - 13 very short colored pencils, 12 red, 1 blue
  - Various albums
    - 1 small album (Poesiealbum) with entries of friends and classmates, first entry dated Strehlen, March 24, 1863, most are from Paul Ehrlich's gymnasium years in Breslau, 1863 March 24 (Package 1)
    - 1 copy of "Die Anaemie", Wien 1898; this is a first edition with blank pages for corrections for 2nd edition. There are many notations by Ehrlich on these pages (Package 1)
    - 1 notebook, with staining experiments in Ehrlich's handwriting. Cover has Ehrlich's drawings (Package 1)
    - 2 monthly calendars for 1903 with entries by Ehrlich (Package 1)
    - 1 leather album for Paul Ehrlich's 50th birthday given to him by his pupils and co-workers, whose names are listed inside, dated (Package 1)
    - 1 diploma of honorary membership to the Physical Society of Frankfurt, bound in an album (Package 1)
    - 2 volumes dedicated to Paul Ehrlich on his 60th birthday entitled: Paul Ehrlich's terminology in word and picture, collected by Dr. Philip Blumenthal, Moscow (Package 1)
    - 1 leather album - necrology album with paper clippings, list of speakers at funeral, photograph of orders, picture of house in which Paul Ehrlich died, picture of funeral from a newspaper (Package 1)
  - Doctoral hats - Death mask
    2 doctoral hats.
    - Dark green velvet hat with golden tassels: University of Oxford, July 14, 1907 (honorary doctorate)., 1907 July 14; Brown envelope with note of date and place inside, outside of envelope has Paul Ehrlich's handwriting (Package 2)
    - Black velvet hat with label of manufacturer I. Gottlieb, Frankfurt a/M. written in ink, Exc. Wirkl. Geh. R., Prof. Dr. P. Ehrlich., Paul Ehrlich death mask (Package 2)
  - Photographs
    - 1 very large photo of Paul Ehrlich (Package 3)
    - 3 glass slides (2 of Paul Ehrlich, 1 of laboratory) (Package 3)
    - 1 Paul Ehrlich photograph has dedication to Martha Marquardt (Package 3)
    - 1 large photograph of the guests at the dinner honoring Hedwig Ehrlich, Oct. 11, 1941 given by the American Social Hygiene Association., 1941 October 11 (Package 3)
      Many of these prints are proofs from the two books on Paul Ehrlich by Martha.
    - Marquardt (Package 3)
      - Photographs of the Paul Ehrlich centennial exhibit done by Hermann Pinkus, 1 folder
      - 1 roll of film "Syphilis und Salvarsan"
  - Paintings and reliefs
    - 1 oil painting on wood with frame of Paul Ehrlich 23" x 32" (artist unknown) (Package 3)
    - 1 plaster relief of Paul Ehrlich dated 1922 16" x 18" (Package 3)
    - 1 small copy of relief 5" x 6" (Package 3)
- Martha Marquardt Material, 2
  1873 Born December 7 in Labes, Pommerania, of Lutheran parents
  1879-1889 Grammar and Middle schooling in Labes
  1890 Emigration to America, stay with family members
  1890-1898 Household work, later learning secretarial skills and holding of several secretarial positions in New York
  1898-1902 Return to Germany and continued employment as bilingual secretary in Worms
  1902-1915 Secretary to Paul Ehrlich in Frankfurt
  1915-1922 Continued employment at the Institute for Experimental Research after Paul Ehrlich's death in 1915
  1922 Dismissal from the Institute
  1924 Publication of book: "Paul Ehrlich als Mensch und Arbeiter"
  1922-1928 Various secretarial positions in Frankfurt
  1928 Move to Berlin to learn laboratory techniques and microcinematography. Making of an educational film on flies
  1929 Move to Paris to learn French
  1930-1939 Voluntary exile in Paris. Support by means of translations, tutoring and various secretarial jobs. Publications of articles in newspapers, as well as the publication of the book: "Die Kleinen Leute von Paris". Expansion of manuscript of first book on Paul Ehrlich. Copyrights of "Paul Ehrlich als Mensch und Arbeiter" sold to Warner Bros. for the film: "Dr. Ehrlich's Magic Bullet".
  1940-1945 Marginal existence in Paris during war years and German occupation
  1946 Emigration to England with the help of Sir Almroth Wright and Sir Alexander Fleming
  1946-1954 Translation of expanded manuscript and publication of German and English versions of book called: Paul Ehrlich
  1946-1954 Moving force behind the publication of "The Collected Papers of Paul Ehrlich", edited by F. Himmelweit, with a foreword by Sir Henry Dale. Partial transcription of 47 volumes of the Paul Ehrlich copy books.
  1954 Participation of the Paul Ehrlich Centennial celebration in Frankfurt
  1956 Died July 14
  Martha Marquardt private correspondence: because of the personal nature of the letters in Box No. 6 and Box No. 7, this correspondence was not incorporated in the remaining correspondence.
  - Martha Marquardt personal correspondence (parents, relatives and friends)
    - Letters and postcards from American relatives and friends, 1903-1915; 24 letters (Box 6, Folder 1)
    - Hubert, Anna (sister), 1901-1902; 2 letters (Box 6, Folder 2)
    - Learsch, Elise (sister), 1902; 1 letter (Box 6, Folder 3)
    - Marie, 1904; 1 letter (Box 6, Folder 3)
    - Unidentified aunt, 1910; 1 letter (Box 6, Folder 3)
    - Marquardt, Auguste (mother), 1901; 12 letters (Box 6, Folder 4)
      Some letters are included by Anna and Georg addressed to parents which were sent on to Martha by her mother.
    - Marquardt, Carl (father), 1892-1902; 12 letters (Box 6, Folder 5)
    - Marquardt, Georg (brother), 1901-1907; 19 letters (Box 6, Folder 6)
    - Marquardt, Georg, 1908-1913; 20 letters (Box 6, Folder 7)
    - Marquardt, Georg, 33 postcards (Box 6, Folder 8)
    - Material pertaining to Georg Marquardt's death, 1913 November
      He was found with his throat slashed in Milwaukee in November 1913. This folder contains correspondence from his landlady, Louis Scheit, as well as various letters, papers and documents returned by Louis Scheit to Martha Marquardt.
      - 7 letters by Louis Scheit to Martha Marquardt (Box 6, Folder 9)
      - Paper clippings (Box 6, Folder 9)
      - 2 drafts of letters by Martha Marquardt (Box 6, Folder 9)
      - 1 letter by Georg, 1913 November 24 (Box 6, Folder 9)
      - 1 letter by Martha Marquardt, 1913 November 14 (Box 6, Folder 9)
      - 3 bills regarding funeral arrangements (Box 6, Folder 9)
      - 7 sympathy cards (Box 6, Folder 9)
      - Death certificate (Box 6, Folder 9)
      - Separation agreement (from wife Lena Marquardt) 1 photo (Box 6, Folder 9)
      - 1 certificate renouncing Prussian citizenship (Box 6, Folder 9)
      - 1 certificate of American citizenship (Box 6, Folder 9)
      - 1 card, requesting Georg to report to work (Box 6, Folder 9)
      - 12 pages from a diary presumably written by Georg (Box 6, Folder 9)
      - 3 telegrams regarding illness and death of parents (Box 6, Folder 10)
  - Hans Hinsen correspondence, (1914-1, 1915-1938, 1916-1931, 1917-0, 1918-1)
    This correspondence with Hans, a son of Lore Hinsen, covers the war years 1914-1918. He was killed in 1918. There are 71 letters, as well as about 50 photographs.
    - Hans Hinsen, 1914-1915; 39 items (Box 7, Folder 1)
    - Hans Hinsen. 1 letter by Lore Hinsen dated Dec. 22, 1918, 1916-1918; 32 items (Box 7, Folder 2)
  - Martha Marquardt Correspondence, 1919 October 23 (Box 7, Folder 3)
    Martha Marquardt's correspondence about Martha Geissler. The 2 Marthas lived together for many years and in a letter to Miss Münch, Martha Marquardt explains why they separated, dated Oct. 23, 1919.
    - 1 letter by J. Münch, Aug. 31, 1919, and a postcard to her, 1919 August 31
  - Correspondance
    - Abelman Arthur, 1924; 1 letter (Box 8, Folder 1)
    - Albrecht, Bruno, 1947-1949; 27 letters (Box 8, Folder 1)
    - Alfthan, Gertrud, 1936; 1 letter (Box 8, Folder 1)
    - Almqvist, Johan, 1921-1924; 12 letters (Box 8, Folder 1)
    - Alt, Konrad, 1921; 1 letter (Box 8, Folder 1)
    - American Medical Association, 1931; 2 letters (Box 8, Folder 1)
    - Ammelburg, 1922; 3 letters (Box 8, Folder 1)
    - Armandias, Louis, 1945-1946; 4 letters (Box 8, Folder 1)
    - Ascoli, Alberto, 1924; 5 letters (Box 8, Folder 1)
    - Ascoli, Maurizio, 1921-1949; 31 letters (Box 8, Folder 1)
    - Ashby, Eric, 1924 1949; 3 letters (Box 8, Folder 1)
    - Aumonerie des Étrangers Protestants en France, 1948-1953; 10 letters (Box 8, Folder 1)
    - Bakeman, George, 1929; 3 letters (Box 8, Folder 2)
    - Baketel, H. Sheridan, 1924; 3 letters (Box 8, Folder 2)
    - Barclays Bank Ltd., 1952; 2 letters (Box 8, Folder 2)
    - Barth, Johann, 1948; 4 letters (Box 8, Folder 2)
    - Bary de, 1947; 1 letter (Box 8, Folder 2)
    - Battes, Marie, 1924 1929; 3 letters (Box 8, Folder 2)
    - Bauer, Hugo, 1924; 1 letter (Box 8, Folder 2)
    - Baum, Vicki, 1937; 9 letters (Box 8, Folder 2)
    - Bayer, Farbwerke, 1948; 2 letters (Box 8, Folder 2)
    - Bechhold, Heinrich, 1922-1931; 10 letters (Box 8, Folder 2)
    - Becker, Heinrich, 1924-1930; 4 letters (Box 8, Folder 2)
    - Beers, 1930; 1 letter (Box 8, Folder 2)
    - Bell, Edwin, 1947; 1 letter (Box 8, Folder 2)
    - Benda, Ludwig, 1922-1950; 32 letters (Box 8, Folder 2)
    - Bergell, Peter, 1924; 3 letters (Box 8, Folder 2)
    - Berliner Illustrierte, 1932; 1 letter (Box 8, Folder 2)
    - Berliner Tageblatt, 1930-1932; 6 letters (Box 8, Folder 2)
    - Berndt, Helmut, 1930-1933; 4 letters (Box 8, Folder 2)
    - Best, 1929-1933; 3 letters (Box 8, Folder 2)
    - Bierbaum, Kurt, 1924-1929; 8 letters (Box 8, Folder 2)
    - Binz, A., 1922; 6 letters (Box 8, Folder 2)
    - Bittner, 1 letter (Box 8, Folder 2)
      first page of letter missing
    - Block, Paul, 1930-1933; 14 letters (Box 8, Folder 2)
    - Blum, Ferdinand, 1949; 3 letters (Box 8, Folder 2)
    - Blumberg, E. F., 1945-1947; 7 letters (Box 8, Folder 2)
    - Blumenthal, G., 1954; 2 letters (Box 8, Folder 2)
    - Bobet, Marcel-Tanneries, 1933; 2 letters (Box 8, Folder 3)
    - Bolduan, Charles, 1921-1951; 15 letters (Box 8, Folder 3)
    - Bondoni, 1924; 2 letters (Box 8, Folder 3)
    - Bormann, Philipp, 1924; 1 letter (Box 8, Folder 3)
    - Brandes, Sarah, 1939; 1 letter (Box 8, Folder 3)
    - Braun, Anna, 1949; 3 letters (Box 8, Folder 3)
      regarding Lore Hinsen
    - Breslau University, 1924; 1 letter (Box 8, Folder 3)
    - Bretzler, 1924; 1 letter (Box 8, Folder 3)
    - British Broadcasting Corporation, 1946-1949; 16 letters (Box 8, Folder 3)
    - British Medical Journal, 1924 1946-1954; 13 letters (Box 8, Folder 3)
    - British Museum, 1947; 1 letter (Box 8, Folder 3)
    - Browning, Carl, 1940-1949; 6 letters (Box 8, Folder 3)
    - Brümmer, Theodor, 1947-1954; 32 letters (Box 8, Folder 3)
    - Bulloch, William, 1921-1924; 11 letters (Box 8, Folder 3)
    - Burr, Victor, 1948; 2 letters (Box 8, Folder 3)
    - Butler, Lynn, 1954; 2 letters (Box 8, Folder 3)
    - Butterworth-Springer Publications, 1950; 1 letter (Box 8, Folder 3)
    - Campaux, C., 1946-1949; 4 letters (Box 8, Folder 4)
    - Carolus Druckerei, 1933; 3 letters (Box 8, Folder 4)
    - Centenary Celebration Organizing Office (Paul Ehrlich), 1954; 7 letters (Box 8, Folder 4)
    - Chaplin, Charles, 1931; 2 letters (Box 8, Folder 4)
    - Chartrain, 1930-1932; 14 letters (Box 8, Folder 4)
    - Chinine, Valja, 1946-1949; 32 letters (Box 8, Folder 4)
    - Clarke, J. E. K., 1946-1956; 3 letters (Box 8, Folder 4)
    - Cohn, Erich, 1949; 1 letter (Box 8, Folder 4)
    - Colebrook, Leonard, 1946-1950; 11 letters (Box 8, Folder 4)
    - Colin, Saul, 1931; 4 letters (Box 8, Folder 4)
    - Cone, Charibel, 1907-1910; 3 letters (Box 8, Folder 4)
    - Cramer, 1933; 1 letter (Box 8, Folder 4)
    - Craxton, 1948; 1 letter (Box 8, Folder 4)
    - Crochard, 1930; 1 letter (Box 8, Folder 4)
    - Curts, Winifred, (Secretary to Sir Henry Dale), 1947-1955; 15 letters (Box 8, Folder 4)
    - Dale, Sir Henry, 1946-1956; 107 letters (Box 8, Folder 5)
    - Danielou, O., 1933; 3 letters (Box 8, Folder 6)
    - Dare, Hector, 1949; 1 letter (Box 8, Folder 6)
    - Delbanco, E., 1924; 1 letter (Box 8, Folder 6)
    - Delestre, Hubert, 1933; 1 letter (Box 8, Folder 6)
    - Dessauer, Friedrich, 1921-1923 1933; 4 letters (Box 8, Folder 6)
      In 1933 Dessauer was imprisoned by the Nazis, and Martha Marquardt started a writing campaign to free him. She wrote to: Madame Curie, Simon Flexner, Karl Landsteiner, Constantin Levaditi, Emile Roux, Sir Almroth Wright, Original letters by: Flexner, Landsteiner, Levaditi & Wright.
    - Deutsch-Amerikanische Petroleum Gesellschaft, 1929; 2 letters (Box 8, Folder 6)
    - Deutsche Bank, 1933; 1 letter (Box 8, Folder 6)
    - Deutsche Verlagsanstalt, 1922-1939; 27 letters (Box 8, Folder 6)
      Including a contract.
    - Diebold, Bernhard, 1922-1924; 4 letters (Box 8, Folder 6)
    - Dossekine, 1948; 1 letter (Box 8, Folder 6)
    - Drevermann, Fritz, 1922; 1 letter (Box 8, Folder 6)
    - Dreyfus, Georges, 1921-1924 1949; 8 letters (Box 8, Folder 6)
    - Dunham, E. K., 1922; 1 letter (Box 8, Folder 6)
    - Dusel, Friedrich, 1932-1933; 5 letters (Box 8, Folder 6)
    - EDA-Bookstore, 1930; 1 letter (Box 9, Folder 1)
    - Ehrhardt, 1946; 1 letter (Box 9, Folder 1)
    - Ehrlich, Hedwig, 1921-1948; 135 letters (Box 9, Folder 2)
    - Ehrlich, S. K., 1954; 2 letters (Box 9, Folder 1)
    - Eigel, Hans, 1934; 1 letter (Box 9, Folder 1)
    - Einhorn Apotheke, 1930; 1 letter (Box 9, Folder 1)
    - Einstein, Albert, 1933 1939 1951; 4 letters (Box 9, Folder 1)
      only copies of Martha Marquardt's 1
    - Enke, Ferdinand, 1921 1947; 5 letters (Box 9, Folder 1)
    - Epstein, Petronella, 1947; 3 letters (Box 9, Folder 1)
    - Farmer, Laurence, 1953; 4 letters (Box 9, Folder 3)
    - Feicht, E., 1930; 1 letter (Box 9, Folder 3)
    - Feihl, 1933; 1 letter (Box 9, Folder 3)
    - Finch, Sir Ernest, 1954; 1 letter (Box 9, Folder 3)
    - Fischer, Gustav, publishing house, 1921-1949; 26 letters (Box 9, Folder 3)
    - Fleischer, Herta, 1930; 15 letters (Box 9, Folder 3)
    - Fleming, Sir Alexander, 1945-1951; 5 letters (Box 9, Folder 3)
    - Flexner, Simon, 1921-1924; 8 letters (Box 9, Folder 3)
    - Flottman, 1933; 3 letters (Box 9, Folder 3)
    - Fluegge, Rudolph, 1950; 1 letter (Box 9, Folder 3)
    - Foerster, Friedrich, 1929-1951; 63 letters (Box 9, Folder 3)
    - Founce, W. K., 1954; 1 letter (Box 9, Folder 3)
    - Fourneau, 1922-1947; 5 letters (Box 9, Folder 3)
    - Fox, Barbara, 1954; 1 letter (Box 9, Folder 3)
    - Francesca, 1932; 1 letter (Box 9, Folder 4)
    - Frankfurter Illustrierte und Zeitung, 1922-1933; 53 letters (Box 9, Folder 4)
    - Frankfurt University-Studentenhilfe, 1924; 1 letter (Box 9, Folder 4)
    - Freeman, John, 1949; 1 letter (Box 9, Folder 4)
    - Freund, Willy, 1924-1956; 65 letters (Box 9, Folder 5)
    - Friedmann, R., 1933; 2 letters (Box 9, Folder 4)
    - Friedrich, 1946-1950 (Box 9, Folder 4)
    - Fröhling, Erna, 1949-1954; 13 letters (Box 9, Folder 4)
    - Fulton, John, 1954; 2 letters (Box 9, Folder 4)
    - Gabriel, Sigmund, 1922-1924; 3 letters (Box 9, Folder 6)
    - Galdston, Iago, 1951-1955; 9 letters (Box 9, Folder 6)
    - Gasser, Herbert, 1950-1951; 3 letters (Box 9, Folder 6)
    - Gazelle, Pierre, 1955; 2 letters (Box 9, Folder 6)
    - Geological Survey and Museum, London, 1947; 3 letters (Box 9, Folder 6)
    - George, Manfred, 1954; 5 letters (Box 9, Folder 6)
    - Gerlach, R., 1933; 1 letter (Box 9, Folder 6)
    - Gerth, E. G., 1930; 2 letters (Box 9, Folder 6)
    - Giese, 1930; 1 letter (Box 9, Folder 6)
    - Gilbaud, Sister M., (regarding Lore Hinsen), 1949; 2 letters (Box 9, Folder 6)
    - Glaser-Goldschmidt, 1932; 1 letter (Box 9, Folder 6)
    - Godard, 1932; 1 letter (Box 9, Folder 6)
    - Goettling, 1933; 1 letter (Box 9, Folder 6)
    - Goldstein, 1933; 1 letter (Box 9, Folder 6)
    - Gontscharoff, Lilly, 1929; 2 letters (Box 9, Folder 6)
    - Gotthardt, Dora, 1929-1930; 16 letters (Box 9, Folder 6)
    - Göttingen University, 1948; 2 letters (Box 9, Folder 6)
    - Götze, 1950; 1 letter (Box 9, Folder 6)
    - Grave, Nadja, 1946; 1 letter (Box 9, Folder 6)
    - Gronemann, Sammy, 1933; 1 letter (Box 9, Folder 6)
    - Gruber, Leni, undated; 1 letter (Box 9, Folder 6)
    - Grzesinski, Albert, 1936; 2 letters (Box 9, Folder 6)
    - Habaru, 1933; 1 letter (Box 9, Folder 7)
    - Hain, Anny, 1947; 2 letters (Box 9, Folder 7)
    - Hamburger Illustrierte, 1933; 3 letters (Box 9, Folder 7)
    - d'Harcourt, Robert, 1932-1933; 10 letters (Box 9, Folder 7)
    - Harmel, Minna, 1931-1933; 3 letters (Box 9, Folder 7)
    - Hata, Sahashiro, 1910-1939; 13 letters (Box 9, Folder 7)
    - Heidelberg University, 1948-1949; 3 letters (Box 9, Folder 7)
    - Heinemann Publishing, 1948-1955; 102 letters (Box 9, Folder 8)
    - Heinsheimer, Emil, 1924; 1 letter (Box 9, Folder 8)
      (See also Epstein, Robert).
    - Helbig, E., 1924; 2 letters (Box 9, Folder 8)
    - Herald, Heinz, 1940; 1 letter (Box 9, Folder 8)
    - Hermening, 1930; 1 letter (Box 9, Folder 8)
    - Hermes, 1929; 3 letters (Box 9, Folder 8)
    - Hengstler, Karl, 1948; 3 letters (Box 9, Folder 8)
    - Hensel, etc. Parcel Agency, 1914-1915; 7 letters (Box 9, Folder 8)
    - Herter Norton-Crena de Iongh, "Polly" Herter (Christian Herter's daughter), 1948; 3 letters (Box 9, Folder 8)
    - Hesses Verlag, 1932; 2 letters (Box 9, Folder 8)
    - Heubner, W., 1921-1924; 4 letters (Box 9, Folder 8)
    - Heyman, Harold, 1951; 1 letter (Box 9, Folder 8)
    - Himmelweit, Fred, 1955 1956; 2 letters (Box 9, Folder 9)
    - Hinsen, Lore, 1924-1949; 15 letters (Box 9, Folder 9)
    - Hirsch, Felix, 1930; 2 letters (Box 9, Folder 9)
    - Hirsch, Karl, 1922; 3 letters (Box 9, Folder 9)
    - Hoeber, Paul, 1923; 3 letters (Box 9, Folder 9)
    - Hoechst Farbwerke, 1949-1954; 6 letters (Box 9, Folder 9)
    - Hoffmann, Erich, 1924; 2 letters (Box 9, Folder 9)
    - Holzer, Lina, 1948; 2 letters (Box 9, Folder 9)
    - Homann, Fritz, 1921; 1 letter (Box 9, Folder 9)
    - Hubel, Hermine, 1930-1936; 9 letters (Box 9, Folder 9)
    - Hunt, Reid, 1921-1940; 11 letters (Box 9, Folder 9)
    - Hygiene Museum, Dresden, 1929-1930; 3 letters (Box 9, Folder 9)
    - Hyman, Thomas, 1940-1945; 5 letters (Box 9, Folder 9)
    - Ignas, Hierodiace, 1931; 2 letters (Box 10, Folder 1)
    - Ihlefeld, 1933; 1 letter (Box 10, Folder 1)
    - Illustrierte für Alle, 1933; 1 letter (Box 10, Folder 1)
    - Imhof, Gottlieb, 1930; 2 letters (Box 10, Folder 1)
    - Income Tax (French), 1939; 1 letter (Box 10, Folder 1)
    - Jacobson, Egon, 1929; 3 letters (Box 10, Folder 2)
    - Jadassohn, 1924; 1 letter (Box 10, Folder 2)
    - Jansen, 1929; 3 letters (Box 10, Folder 2)
    - Jenner Institute, 1946; 1 letter (Box 10, Folder 2)
    - Kadereit, Marie, 1923; 2 letters (Box 10, Folder 3)
    - Kahn, Magda, 1929-1930; 3 letters (Box 10, Folder 3)
    - Karrer, Paul, 1937-1950; 9 letters (Box 10, Folder 3)
    - Katholischer Deutscher Frauenbund, 1929; 1 letter (Box 10, Folder 3)
    - Kauffmann, Arthur, 1929-1930; 3 letters (Box 10, Folder 3)
    - Keller, Max, 1929-1931; 10 letters (Box 10, Folder 3)
    - Keystone View Co., 1932; 1 letter (Box 10, Folder 3)
    - Kicksch, Leni, 1926 1932; 2 and 15 small photographs (Box 10, Folder 3)
    - Killius, Hans, undated; 1 letter (Box 10, Folder 3)
    - Kirchensteuer Zahlstelle, 1930; 2 letters (Box 10, Folder 3)
    - Klinkhart, Traude, 1929-1930; 4 letters (Box 10, Folder 3)
    - Klostermann, Eckard, 1922; 2 letters (Box 10, Folder 3)